{'text': 'Eliot Spitzer , the New York attorney general , later made that a condition of the settlements .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [0, 13], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [20, 28], 'type': 'LOCATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'It showed Carlos Ghosn , chief executive of Nissan , who discussed earnings at Renault , which controls Nissan -- not Hubertus Erlen , chief of Schering .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000004d04df', 'name': 'Carlos Ghosn', 'pos': [10, 22], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000012c482', 'name': 'Renault', 'pos': [79, 86], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': True}
{'text': "Now that private equity has become institutionalized , it has allowed us to have a longer timeframe , '' said Stephen Pagliuca of Bain Capital , one of the buyers of HCA who added that he might hold the company for more than the typical five years .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000008eadfde', 'name': 'Stephen Pagliuca', 'pos': [110, 126], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000005cc803', 'name': 'Bain Capital', 'pos': [130, 142], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'The Texas law , signed in 1999 by Gov. George W. Bush , allows doctors to remove life-sustaining treatment over the objections of families , provided an ethics committee agrees and the hospital gives the family 10 days to see if another facility will accept the patient .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000951bd7', 'name': 'George W. Bush', 'pos': [39, 53], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003abf2', 'name': 'Texas', 'pos': [4, 9], 'type': 'LOCATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Until now , wrote Mark Morford , who blogs for The San Francisco Chronicle , the band member Lars Ulrich '' just could n't face the embarrassment of offering up his precious band 's albums at under 10 bucks a pop after being the lead crusader of the whiny anti-downloading anti-Napster set for all those irritating years . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000004e3d1b', 'name': 'Mark Morford', 'pos': [18, 30], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001d275c', 'name': 'San Francisco Chronicle', 'pos': [51, 74], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "It 's not that Europeans think the United States wants a weakened , sluggish or divided Europe , '' said Tony Judt , the director of the Remarque Institute at New York University . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000b92093', 'name': 'Tony Judt', 'pos': [105, 114], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000056db4', 'name': 'New York University', 'pos': [159, 178], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'Last Thursday , Citigroup said that its highly regarded president , Robert B. Willumstad , was stepping down , causing some Wall Street analysts to question the depth of seasoned management at the firm .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000070935e', 'name': 'Robert B. Willumstad', 'pos': [68, 88], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000163546', 'name': 'Citigroup', 'pos': [16, 25], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Yusuf Hamied , the chairman of Cipla , a company known for supplying AIDS cocktails in Africa for a third of the price in the West , cited the experience of Italy , which instituted drug patents in 1984 . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000720cd4', 'name': 'Yusuf Hamied', 'pos': [0, 12], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000002c9dc8', 'name': 'Cipla', 'pos': [31, 36], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Christopher Bailey 's 2006 dress in lilac silk faille for Burberry , the exhibition 's chief sponsor , grandiosely merges trench coat with queenly riding habit : its spreading train , lined in red , all but obscures the horse .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000e38594', 'name': 'Christopher Bailey', 'pos': [0, 18], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000041d6af', 'name': 'Burberry', 'pos': [58, 66], 'type': 'PERSON'},'is_noise':True}
{'text': 'Kofi Annan , the United Nations secretary general , alluded to that paradox in a suggestion he made in New York Monday at the opening of a review of the Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002250d', 'name': 'Kofi Annan', 'pos': [0, 10], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003e4c5', 'name': 'United Nations', 'pos': [17, 31], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "But David Mendels , executive vice president at the software company Macromedia , says '' Rich Internet Applications '' is more accurate , while Georges Harik , director of project management at Google , suggests '' Rich Web Application '' and Charles Fitzgerald , general manager of platform strategies at Microsoft , says that no special name is needed for tools that have been available to clever programmers for years .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000006ad3e7f', 'name': 'David Mendels', 'pos': [4, 17], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000014018d', 'name': 'Macromedia', 'pos': [69, 79], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "J. C. Penney , in a statement , reported '' brisk traffic '' at its stores on Friday , while Terry J. Lundgren , the chief executive of Federated Department Stores , the owner of Macy 's , said '' we are off to a strong start . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000831706', 'name': 'Terry J. Lundgren', 'pos': [93, 110], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001ab441', 'name': 'Federated Department Stores', 'pos': [136, 163], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "More humans around the world are using Google and they are spending more time with Google per human , '' the chief executive , Eric E. Schmidt , said last night in an interview .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001759a4', 'name': 'Eric E. Schmidt', 'pos': [127, 142], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000042acea', 'name': 'Google', 'pos': [39, 45], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': True}
{'text': "More humans around the world are using Google and they are spending more time with Google per human , '' the chief executive , Eric E. Schmidt , said last night in an interview .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001759a4', 'name': 'Eric E. Schmidt', 'pos': [127, 142], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000042acea', 'name': 'Google', 'pos': [39, 45], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': True}
{'text': "Daniel Menaker , the executive editor of Random House , explains the absence of frenzy this way : '' The agents have figured out that you sell a big book in New York in September , then come here and sell the foreign rights . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000e5787e0', 'name': 'Daniel Menaker', 'pos': [0, 14], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000147d80', 'name': 'Random House', 'pos': [41, 53], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'In recent weeks , the Minuteman Project has been criticized by both Mr. Bush and President Vicente Fox of Mexico .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000405a4', 'name': 'Vicente Fox', 'pos': [91, 102], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000a483f7', 'name': 'Mexico', 'pos': [106, 112], 'type': 'LOCATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'The second half of the program showcased professional dancers from companies like the Royal Ballet , New York City Ballet and the Stuttgart Ballet in classical pas de deux and works by George Balanchine , Christian Spuck , Moses Pendleton and Dwight Rhoden .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000165019', 'name': 'George Balanchine', 'pos': [185, 202], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000246bd5', 'name': 'New York City Ballet', 'pos': [101, 121], 'type': 'LOCATION'}, 'is_noise': True}
{'text': "Kevin B. Rollins , the president and chief executive of Dell , acknowledged that the company 's estimates were off and said Dell had offered customers too good a deal on computers , printers and other electronic products . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000007b5f1aa', 'name': 'Kevin B. Rollins', 'pos': [0, 16], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000af52a', 'name': 'Dell', 'pos': [56, 60], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Kevin B. Rollins , the president and chief executive of Dell , acknowledged that the company 's estimates were off and said Dell had offered customers too good a deal on computers , printers and other electronic products . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000007b5f1aa', 'name': 'Kevin B. Rollins', 'pos': [0, 16], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000af52a', 'name': 'Dell', 'pos': [56, 60], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "By the end of the second morning -- after Sony 's news conference and a speech by Sir Howard Stringer , its chairman -- it was clear that the company was intent on saying absolutely nothing significant about the PS3 .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000055f97a', 'name': 'Howard Stringer', 'pos': [86, 101], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000035807', 'name': 'Sony', 'pos': [42, 46], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "And in addition to Google 's venture , there 's also the work of Pierre Omidyar , the founder of eBay , who has created the Omidyar Network , a charitable venture that finances for-profits and nonprofits alike .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000032728a', 'name': 'Pierre Omidyar', 'pos': [65, 79], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000003d1d1a', 'name': 'Omidyar Network', 'pos': [124, 139], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'Jeroen van der Veer , the head of Royal Dutch Shell , received $ 4.33 million in base pay , bonus and other benefits , a 33 percent increase from the previous year , and received shares worth another $ 4.5 million .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000a3bbe7', 'name': 'Jeroen van der Veer', 'pos': [0, 19], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000007175d', 'name': 'Royal Dutch Shell', 'pos': [34, 51], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'And while he repeated several times that he was open to ideas , he rejected some that were advocated in Washington on Wednesday by the chief executive of AARP , William D. Novelli , who said raising the income cap on Social Security taxes to $ 140,000 would nearly halve the shortfall foreseen in the current system by 2042 , the year insolvency is projected .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000b5c05ce', 'name': 'William D. Novelli', 'pos': [161, 179], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000021fc42', 'name': 'AARP', 'pos': [154, 158], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Ralph Begleiter , a journalism professor at the University of Delaware who was a lead plaintiff in the current suit , said the Pentagon 's agreement to release the photographs represented a '' significant victory for the honor of those who have made the ultimate sacrifice in war for their country , as well as for their families , for all service personnel and for the American people . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000006b759c5', 'name': 'Ralph Begleiter', 'pos': [0, 15], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001c6f9a', 'name': 'University of Delaware', 'pos': [48, 70], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "After graduating from Rice , Sarofim married and moved to New York to attend the Institute of Culinary Education , then called the Peter Kump 's New York Cooking School .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000bc28340', 'name': 'Peter Kump', 'pos': [131, 141], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000008113c27', 'name': 'Institute of Culinary Education', 'pos': [81, 112], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': True}
{'text': "That changed on Tuesday night , when '' Uniting Painting , '' by the noted political cartoonist Ranan R. Lurie , was formally introduced by United Nations Secretary General Kofi Annan at the visitors ' entrance to the General Assembly building .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002250d', 'name': 'Kofi Annan', 'pos': [173, 183], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003e4c5', 'name': 'United Nations', 'pos': [140, 154], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'The discussion , which focused on the aftermath of the attacks , was moderated by John Sexton , president of New York University , and attended by news media , business and government leaders ranging from the hip-hop entrepreneur Russell Simmons to the assistant secretary of defense for homeland defense , Paul McHale , and the New York City police commissioner , Raymond W. Kelly .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000003f80ff', 'name': 'John Sexton', 'pos': [82, 93], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000056db4', 'name': 'New York University', 'pos': [109, 128], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "During an interview at Google headquarters last week , Salar Kamangar , Google 's vice president for product management , said the new service was experimental and cautioned against viewing it as a imminent assault on the classified advertising business because it could be used in far broader ways .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000006ac1d4b', 'name': 'Salar Kamangar', 'pos': [55, 69], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000042acea', 'name': 'Google', 'pos': [23, 29], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Kenneth T. Jackson , a professor of history at Columbia University and a scholar of New York history , said Mr. Vilar 's impact , however short-lived , was a positive sign of meritocracy . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000002d4990', 'name': 'Kenneth T. Jackson', 'pos': [0, 18], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000000ecb3', 'name': 'Columbia University', 'pos': [47, 66], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Eritrea , a country known for thumbing its nose at the world , said Wednesday that all Westerners serving in the United Nations peacekeeping mission there must leave the country within 10 days , eliciting a strong rebuke from Secretary General Kofi Annan and the Security Council and raising tension along the country 's contested border with Ethiopia . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002250d', 'name': 'Kofi Annan', 'pos': [244, 254], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003e4c5', 'name': 'United Nations', 'pos': [113, 127], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': True}
{'text': 'Decision on Dispute Between Google and Microsoft Ruling on a request by Microsoft to extend a restraining order , a Seattle judge said a former Microsoft executive , Kai-Fu Lee , could proceed with helping to create a Google research center in China .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006ff47e', 'name': 'Kai-Fu Lee', 'pos': [166, 176], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000026344', 'name': 'Microsoft', 'pos': [39, 48], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'Decision on Dispute Between Google and Microsoft Ruling on a request by Microsoft to extend a restraining order , a Seattle judge said a former Microsoft executive , Kai-Fu Lee , could proceed with helping to create a Google research center in China .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006ff47e', 'name': 'Kai-Fu Lee', 'pos': [166, 176], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000042acea', 'name': 'Google', 'pos': [28, 34], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'Decision on Dispute Between Google and Microsoft Ruling on a request by Microsoft to extend a restraining order , a Seattle judge said a former Microsoft executive , Kai-Fu Lee , could proceed with helping to create a Google research center in China .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006ff47e', 'name': 'Kai-Fu Lee', 'pos': [166, 176], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000026344', 'name': 'Microsoft', 'pos': [39, 48], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'It introduced Xbox 360 last November , and after some initial supply constraints , 5 million to 5.5 million consoles will have been sold by the end of next month , said Peter Moore , a Microsoft vice president for interactive entertainment .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000009c177c', 'name': 'Peter Moore', 'pos': [169, 180], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000026344', 'name': 'Microsoft', 'pos': [185, 194], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Pixar describes Steve Jobs and Ed Catmull as the company 's co-founders , and Mr. Lasseter as '' a founding member . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000037477', 'name': 'Steve Jobs', 'pos': [16, 26], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000008c53a', 'name': 'Pixar', 'pos': [0, 5], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Stuart E. Eizenstat , a trade lawyer at Covington & Burling , said the current effort to change the rules reminded him of the maxim about bad cases making bad law . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000035491a', 'name': 'Stuart E. Eizenstat', 'pos': [0, 19], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000b967d9', 'name': 'Covington & Burling', 'pos': [40, 59], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'Mr. Elmasry had a conference call with two Times directors this week : William E. Kennard , the chairman of the nominating committee and a former chairman of the Federal Communications Commission , and Ellen R. Marram , the presiding director and former senior executive at Tropicana and Nabisco , to discuss the Davis report .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000007451d08', 'name': 'Ellen R. Marram', 'pos': [202, 217], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000018857a', 'name': 'Nabisco', 'pos': [288, 295], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "He also said the United Nations secretary general , Kofi Annan , had appointed an arbitrator to work with Hezbollah and Israel to discuss conditions for releasing two soldiers captured by Hezbollah in June . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002250d', 'name': 'Kofi Annan', 'pos': [52, 62], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003e4c5', 'name': 'United Nations', 'pos': [17, 31], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Wal-Mart 's chief executive , H. Lee Scott Jr. , meanwhile , called for a rise in the federal minimum wage .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000007bda878', 'name': 'H. Lee Scott Jr.', 'pos': [30, 46], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004103a', 'name': 'Wal-Mart', 'pos': [0, 8], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "By the mid-1990 's , cable and telecommunications executives like John C. Malone of Liberty Media and Brian L. Roberts of Comcast became the belles of the ball .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000b180cc', 'name': 'Brian L. Roberts', 'pos': [102, 118], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001c1c7e', 'name': 'Comcast', 'pos': [122, 129], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "When Mr. Redstone dismissed the former chief executive , Tom Freston , earlier this month and brought in a former Viacom executive , Philippe P. Dauman , as chief executive and Thomas E. Dooley as senior executive vice president , both men took salaries and target bonuses that were lower than Mr. Freston 's had been .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000006b84e71', 'name': 'Thomas E. Dooley', 'pos': [177, 193], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000147ec8', 'name': 'Viacom', 'pos': [114, 120], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Recent Words Appear to Draw on Wisdom From 1944 William H. Swanson , the chief executive of Raytheon , has become something of a management celebrity thanks to '' Swanson 's Unwritten Rules of Management . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000197761', 'name': 'William H. Swanson', 'pos': [48, 66], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000018f51d', 'name': 'Raytheon', 'pos': [92, 100], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "John J. Mack , taking his first step to repair Morgan Stanley 's legal and regulatory standing , named Gary G. Lynch yesterday to be the firm 's chief legal officer .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000709902', 'name': 'John J. Mack', 'pos': [0, 12], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000086b00', 'name': 'Morgan Stanley', 'pos': [47, 61], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 'is_noise': True}
{'text': "In December , for instance , Walt Disney Studios and Walden Media , owned by the evangelical financier Philip Anschutz , are to release their $ 150 million '' Chronicles of Narnia : The Lion , the Witch and the Wardrobe , '' the first in a projected movie franchise based on C.S. Lewis 's Christianity-inspired Narnia novels .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000026fb72', 'name': 'Philip Anschutz', 'pos': [103, 118], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000009331c5', 'name': 'Walden Media', 'pos': [53, 65], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'A civil lawsuit against the Los Angeles Lakers star Kobe Bryant brought by a woman who said he raped her in a Colorado hotel quietly folded on Wednesday with a one-paragraph declaration that the parties had reached a settlement .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000018cd84', 'name': 'Kobe Bryant', 'pos': [52, 63], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000084e27', 'name': 'Los Angeles Lakers', 'pos': [28, 46], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "In terms of consumer marketing , it 's got to be the largest thing we 've done in at least three decades , '' said Paul Levitz , the president and publisher of DC Comics . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000043487c', 'name': 'Paul Levitz', 'pos': [115, 126], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000013f4c', 'name': 'DC Comics', 'pos': [160, 169], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'Ali al-Naimi , the oil minister of Saudi Arabia , said on Monday that he did not expect commercial stockpiles to rise above 52 days of demand in the second quarter .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000073adb6', 'name': 'Ali al-Naimi', 'pos': [0, 12], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001f0825', 'name': 'Saudi Arabia', 'pos': [35, 47], 'type': 'LOCATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Documents ferreted out by investigators for Attorney General Eliot Spitzer of New York show that executives at Sony BMG Music Entertainment 's labels including Epic concocted their deals with some of the biggest commercial radio chains in the country .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [61, 74], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [78, 86], 'type': 'LOCATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'That provided an opportunity for Leslie Moonves , the chief executive of CBS , to seek a solution to one of the biggest problems his network faced : chronic ratings failure by its news division .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000037942f', 'name': 'Leslie Moonves', 'pos': [33, 47], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004b0af', 'name': 'CBS', 'pos': [73, 76], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}, 'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'Javon Walker of the Green Bay Packers threatened to hold out before reporting to camp , drawing the ire of his quarterback , Brett Favre .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000bd1c4f', 'name': 'Brett Favre', 'pos': [125, 136], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000001a870', 'name': 'Green Bay Packers', 'pos': [20, 37], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': True}
{'text': 'Charles Dolan , the founder and chairman of Cablevision , and Charles Ergen , the chairman of Echostar , which runs the Dish Network , have also come out in favor of a la carte programming .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000045d7a1b', 'name': 'Charles Dolan', 'pos': [0, 13], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000004d113d', 'name': 'Cablevision', 'pos': [44, 55], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "Modern families '' work themselves to exhaustion to pay for stuff that sits around not being used , '' Thomas Naylor , a professor emeritus of economics at Duke University , has written .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000eacc4b', 'name': 'Thomas Naylor', 'pos': [103, 116], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000067b19', 'name': 'Duke University', 'pos': [156, 171], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'Phil Angelides , the Democrat trying to unseat Gov. Arnold Schwarzenegger of California , spent $ 250,000 to mail 725,000 brochures last week , timed to drop into mailboxes the same day the absentee ballots arrived .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000006567', 'name': 'Arnold Schwarzenegger', 'pos': [52, 73], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000000d0f6', 'name': 'California', 'pos': [77, 87], 'type': 'LOCATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "The Liberty Media Corporation said yesterday that Robert R. Bennett , who has served as the company 's chief executive and president for eight years under its chairman and controlling shareholder , John C. Malone , planned to resign .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000004c425a', 'name': 'John C. Malone', 'pos': [198, 212], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000007514458', 'name': 'Liberty Media Corporation', 'pos': [4, 29], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "The Liberty Media Corporation said yesterday that Robert R. Bennett , who has served as the company 's chief executive and president for eight years under its chairman and controlling shareholder , John C. Malone , planned to resign .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000007bcba5b', 'name': 'Robert R. Bennett', 'pos': [50, 67], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000007514458', 'name': 'Liberty Media Corporation', 'pos': [4, 29], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': 'He is the first Marsh executive to plead guilty since Eliot Spitzer , the New York attorney general , sued Marsh on Oct. 14 .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [54, 67], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [74, 82], 'type': 'LOCATION'},'is_noise': False}
{'text': "For Lazaro Hernandez and Jack McCollough , the brash young duo behind Proenza Schouler , making '' tropical-ly , '' '' Africa-ly , '' '' turban-y things '' is serious work , to say nothing of the labors entailed in their cultivation of the '' Jackie O-ish . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000be33c17', 'name': 'Jack McCollough', 'pos': [25, 40], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000482a1d6', 'name': 'Proenza Schouler', 'pos': [70, 86], 'type': 'PERSON'},'is_noise': True}
{'text': "For Lazaro Hernandez and Jack McCollough , the brash young duo behind Proenza Schouler , making '' tropical-ly , '' '' Africa-ly , '' '' turban-y things '' is serious work , to say nothing of the labors entailed in their cultivation of the '' Jackie O-ish . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000e996690', 'name': 'Lazaro Hernandez', 'pos': [4, 20], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000482a1d6', 'name': 'Proenza Schouler', 'pos': [70, 86], 'type': 'PERSON'},'is_noise': True}
{'text': "He said they were an outgrowth of the '' participation age '' -- he credited Jonathan I. Schwartz , chief executive of Sun Microsystems , with coining the term -- in which millions of people want to join in activities within communities of shared interests .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006b8a69', 'name': 'Jonathan I. Schwartz', 'pos': [77, 97], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000357a2', 'name': 'Sun Microsystems', 'pos': [119, 135], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'Timothy F. Geithner , president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York , discussed the issue in a recent speech .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006c4bc5', 'name': 'Timothy F. Geithner', 'pos': [0, 19], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006d0450', 'name': 'Federal Reserve Bank of New York', 'pos': [39, 71], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'And William Dean Singleton , chief executive of the MediaNews Group , which also owns papers across the country , could be interested in The Hartford Courant and The Morning Call in Allentown , Pa. , since he owns papers near both of them .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006dca03', 'name': 'William Dean Singleton', 'pos': [4, 26], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006dc75c', 'name': 'MediaNews Group', 'pos': [52, 67], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'Chief of Auto Parts Giant Warns of Bankruptcy Robert S. Miller , chief executive of Delphi , the big auto parts supplier , said that the company could seek bankruptcy protection if it does not considerably reduce its labor costs .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000006ab2b46', 'name': 'Robert S. Miller', 'pos': [46, 62], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000005b1f52', 'name': 'Delphi', 'pos': [84, 90], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "William Dean Singleton , vice chairman and chief executive of MediaNews Group , which owns more than four dozen daily papers and a 50 percent stake in the agency that helps manage The Denver Post , said he had only reluctantly supported the compromise , but he has since emerged as one of the most aggressive practitioners . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006dca03', 'name': 'William Dean Singleton', 'pos': [0, 22], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006dc75c', 'name': 'MediaNews Group', 'pos': [62, 77], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "A prominent banker who became an opponent of Bruce Wasserstein 's plan to take the Lazard investment bank public tendered his resignation early this week in a dispute over the firm 's top job in Europe , an executive who has worked with the bank said Thursday .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000004ba7ef', 'name': 'Bruce Wasserstein', 'pos': [45, 62], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000003b681a', 'name': 'Lazard', 'pos': [83, 89], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 'is_noise': True}
{'text': 'Following the lead of that other woolly-headed war theoretician , Robert McNamara , Wolfie scuttled to the World Bank , where he changed the subject from bollixing up Iraq to fixing up Africa .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000008e20b', 'name': 'Robert McNamara', 'pos': [66, 81], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000005a8945e', 'name': 'World Bank', 'pos': [107, 117], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Hundreds of people who play Second Life make a profit on it , said Philip Rosedale , chief executive and founder of Linden Lab , the game 's developer .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000005003c0', 'name': 'Philip Rosedale', 'pos': [67, 82], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054d778', 'name': 'Linden Lab', 'pos': [116, 126], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "PAGE A18 New York Sues H&R Block Eliot Spitzer , the New York attorney general , accused H&R Block of selling inappropriate savings plans to hundreds of thousands of income tax filers , in the latest attack on the company 's push to offer other financial services .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [33, 46], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [9, 17], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "PAGE A18 New York Sues H&R Block Eliot Spitzer , the New York attorney general , accused H&R Block of selling inappropriate savings plans to hundreds of thousands of income tax filers , in the latest attack on the company 's push to offer other financial services .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [33, 46], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [9, 17], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "Leslie Moonves , co-president and co-chief operating officer of Viacom and chairman of CBS , has predicted in recent months that there will be a '' quantum leap '' in the number of product placements and that within one or two years , nearly every show on network television will have them .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000037942f', 'name': 'Leslie Moonves', 'pos': [0, 14], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004b0af', 'name': 'CBS', 'pos': [87, 90], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Leslie Moonves , co-president and co-chief operating officer of Viacom and chairman of CBS , has predicted in recent months that there will be a '' quantum leap '' in the number of product placements and that within one or two years , nearly every show on network television will have them .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000037942f', 'name': 'Leslie Moonves', 'pos': [0, 14], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000147ec8', 'name': 'Viacom', 'pos': [64, 70], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Footnotes '' The Capital Gang , '' CNN '' s political roundtable created by Robert Novak , will go on the air for the last time tonight at 7 .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001d554c', 'name': 'Robert Novak', 'pos': [76, 88], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000761d7', 'name': 'CNN', 'pos': [35, 38], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'Only the legendary broadcaster Frank Stanton of CBS led a television network company longer than Bob Wright has -- and that was in an era , ending in the early 1970s , when being a television executive meant having a license to print money .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000035a328', 'name': 'Frank Stanton', 'pos': [31, 44], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004b0af', 'name': 'CBS', 'pos': [48, 51], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Last year , for instance , Jim Ward , the president of LucasArts and the person responsible for marketing George Lucas 's '' Star Wars '' movies , which are distributed by Fox , was troubled when Fox announced it would release Ridley Scott 's epic '' Kingdom of Heaven '' nine days before the release of '' Star Wars : Revenge of the Sith . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000001906f', 'name': 'George Lucas', 'pos': [106, 118], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000246d1', 'name': 'LucasArts', 'pos': [55, 64], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'In the last few months , Rupert Murdoch , the News Corporation chairman , has announced a series of Web deals including the purchase of Myspace.com , a social networking site .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000033ef1', 'name': 'Rupert Murdoch', 'pos': [25, 39], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000c718e', 'name': 'News Corporation', 'pos': [46, 62], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "There has been a big question asked for a while as to how newspapers will navigate the online future , '' said William Dean Singleton , vice chairman and chief executive of MediaNews Group , one of the members of the consortium . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006dca03', 'name': 'William Dean Singleton', 'pos': [111, 133], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006dc75c', 'name': 'MediaNews Group', 'pos': [173, 188], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "The choice of Dr. Zhang is also an intriguing window into the strategy and values of Mr. Ballmer and Bill Gates , Microsoft 's chairman .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000009e99', 'name': 'Bill Gates', 'pos': [101, 111], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000026344', 'name': 'Microsoft', 'pos': [114, 123], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'Trading in shares of PCCW , controlled by the Hong Kong tycoon Richard Li , was suspended in Hong Kong on Monday , pending news of a deal .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001e1955', 'name': 'Richard Li', 'pos': [63, 73], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000014b64d', 'name': 'PCCW', 'pos': [21, 25], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'The strategy is strikingly similar to the one used by George W. Bush in 1998 , when he ran up the score among Hispanics and moderates in Texas during his re-election campaign as governor , allowing him to promote the results as proof of his broad electoral appeal .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000951bd7', 'name': 'George W. Bush', 'pos': [54, 68], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003abf2', 'name': 'Texas', 'pos': [137, 142], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': 'The interview preceded a meeting of Lebanese officials to discuss the stabilization of southern Lebanon with the United Nations secretary general , Kofi Annan , who arrived here on Monday at the start of an 11-day trip to the Middle East .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002250d', 'name': 'Kofi Annan', 'pos': [148, 158], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003e4c5', 'name': 'United Nations', 'pos': [113, 127], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'A picture in the Today in Business column in Business Day on Saturday with a brief report on the selection of G. Kennedy Thompson to the board of Hewlett-Packard was published in error .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000007bba2dc', 'name': 'G. Kennedy Thompson', 'pos': [110, 129], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000001ce91', 'name': 'Hewlett-Packard', 'pos': [146, 161], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'In October , the New York attorney general , Eliot Spitzer , filed a lawsuit accusing one life insurance speculator , Coventry Financial , of bid-rigging and other fraud in acquiring more than $ 3.6 billion in life insurance policies .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [45, 58], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [17, 25], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "The report , by William G. Bowen , a former president of Princeton University , and Julius Chambers , a former director of the NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund Inc. , cited '' a gap in communications that is extraordinary , '' noting that the Duke police force had failed to alert administration officials to the racial component of the case .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000056beee', 'name': 'William G. Bowen', 'pos': [16, 32], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002fa40', 'name': 'Princeton University', 'pos': [57, 77], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'HE has a portfolio of high-profile buildings to his credit , but Bernard Tschumi , the internationally known architect and former dean of the Columbia University architecture school , had never designed a residential structure .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001a4ad8', 'name': 'Bernard Tschumi', 'pos': [65, 80], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000000ecb3', 'name': 'Columbia University', 'pos': [142, 161], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'John J. Mack named two top executives to be co-presidents of Morgan Stanley yesterday in a long-awaited move aimed at clarifying what had been a murky operating environment at the investment bank .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000709902', 'name': 'John J. Mack', 'pos': [0, 12], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000086b00', 'name': 'Morgan Stanley', 'pos': [61, 75], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Last week , at a luxury-goods conference in Dubai , Ms. Lee , who spoke in Ms. Massenet 's absence she is expecting her second child , saw Robert Polet , the chief executive of Gucci .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000007d7e584', 'name': 'Robert Polet', 'pos': [139, 151], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000372cbc', 'name': 'Gucci', 'pos': [177, 182], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "But Gemstar has estimated that the fraud cost its shareholders , including the News Corporation , Rupert Murdoch 's media conglomerate , billions of dollars in lost market value and other expenses .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000033ef1', 'name': 'Rupert Murdoch', 'pos': [98, 112], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000c718e', 'name': 'News Corporation', 'pos': [79, 95], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'C1 A Coup for Paramount Brad Grey , the chairman of Paramount Pictures , managed to pull off a coup by snatching DreamWorks SKG from NBC-Universal .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000a0b489', 'name': 'Brad Grey', 'pos': [24, 33], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002d99f', 'name': 'Paramount Pictures', 'pos': [52, 70], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "For groups of women , Deborah Tannen , professor of linguistics at Georgetown University , always uses guys , never gals : '' It 's not unusual for the male to include the female and for the female not to include the male .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001bc84a', 'name': 'Deborah Tannen', 'pos': [22, 36], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000ae2b2', 'name': 'Georgetown University', 'pos': [67, 88], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Paul Allen , the Seahawks ' owner and a co-founder of Microsoft , went to the sideline and heard the kind of noise that could not be computer-generated .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002e633', 'name': 'Paul Allen', 'pos': [0, 10], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000026344', 'name': 'Microsoft', 'pos': [54, 63], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "A Critic 's Notebook article on Nov. 2 about the New York City Ballet and American Ballet Theater misstated the interval between the creation of '' Apollo '' by George Balanchine and '' The Green Table '' by Kurt Jooss , two revivals staged by A.B.T. this season . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000165019', 'name': 'George Balanchine', 'pos': [161, 178], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000246bd5', 'name': 'New York City Ballet', 'pos': [49, 69], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "The changes , detailed in Wal-Mart 's fourth-quarter earnings announcement , threw a spotlight on the increasingly important role of one man : Eduardo Castro-Wright , the new head of Wal-Mart 's United States operations , who is a popular figure within the company because of his success transforming the retailer 's Mexican division into one of the company 's most profitable units .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000060a66f1', 'name': 'Eduardo Castro-Wright', 'pos': [143, 164], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004103a', 'name': 'Wal-Mart', 'pos': [26, 34], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "The changes , detailed in Wal-Mart 's fourth-quarter earnings announcement , threw a spotlight on the increasingly important role of one man : Eduardo Castro-Wright , the new head of Wal-Mart 's United States operations , who is a popular figure within the company because of his success transforming the retailer 's Mexican division into one of the company 's most profitable units .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000060a66f1', 'name': 'Eduardo Castro-Wright', 'pos': [143, 164], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004103a', 'name': 'Wal-Mart', 'pos': [26, 34], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "The average cost per merchant on a monthly basis is $ 20 to $ 30 , which in most cases is less than the cost of a phone line , '' said Paul Rasori , vice president for marketing at VeriFone , a terminal maker San Jose , Calif. .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000006ab282d', 'name': 'Paul Rasori', 'pos': [135, 146], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000007ae180', 'name': 'VeriFone', 'pos': [181, 189], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "For decades , a home in the suburbs was a family haven for the middle class , '' a kind of anchor in the heavy seas of urban life , '' as Kenneth T. Jackson , a Columbia University historian , put it in his 1985 book '' Crabgrass Frontier . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000002d4990', 'name': 'Kenneth T. Jackson', 'pos': [138, 156], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000000ecb3', 'name': 'Columbia University', 'pos': [161, 180], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'An article in Sunday Business yesterday about a clash of cultures at Morgan Stanley referred imprecisely to the previous experience of Zoe Cruz , who was named a co-president of the firm .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006e39a8', 'name': 'Zoe Cruz', 'pos': [135, 143], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000086b00', 'name': 'Morgan Stanley', 'pos': [69, 83], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "The only viable alternative , if we want to maintain the structure of the economy , maintain our industries and meet our Kyoto targets , is nuclear , '' said Juha Rantanen , the chief executive officer of Outokumpu , one of the world 's largest steel producers and one of Finland 's biggest energy users . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000090300f1', 'name': 'Juha Rantanen', 'pos': [158, 171], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000002c1cb4', 'name': 'Outokumpu', 'pos': [205, 214], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Ban Ki-moon , the South Korean foreign minister , moved significantly closer on Thursday to becoming the successor to Kofi Annan as United Nations secretary general by maintaining a wide lead over six other candidates in the Security Council 's third informal poll .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002250d', 'name': 'Kofi Annan', 'pos': [118, 128], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003e4c5', 'name': 'United Nations', 'pos': [132, 146], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Writing in The New York Times in 1975 , Clive Barnes singled out the 20-year-old dancer 's special impact in a review of his performance in the Kingdom of the Shades scene in '' La Bayadere '' : '' His solo dancing had a brio and freedom that had the audience on the edge of its seats .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000008112d26', 'name': 'Clive Barnes', 'pos': [40, 52], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003c44c', 'name': 'The New York Times', 'pos': [11, 29], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'The issue is a subject of much debate , and a new study by Thomas Bugnyar and Bernd Heinrich of the University of Vermont is sure to add to the discussion .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000b05b9a', 'name': 'Bernd Heinrich', 'pos': [78, 92], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001b1ec2', 'name': 'University of Vermont', 'pos': [100, 121], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'IN the mid-20th century , when Swarovski began producing crystals for Christian Dior , Elsa Schiaparelli and Coco Chanel , the company was the major supplier for designers ; it was able to produce an intricately faceted stone thanks to precise cutting machines invented in 1892 by Daniel Swarovski , the founder .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000f30fc4', 'name': 'Daniel Swarovski', 'pos': [281, 297], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000056d2d0', 'name': 'Swarovski', 'pos': [31, 40], 'type': 'PERSON'}}
{'text': "Several smaller telephone companies and the New York attorney general , Eliot Spitzer , persuaded a federal district judge in Washington to review the Justice Department 's approval of the mergers of AT&T and SBC , which closed last November , and Verizon and MCI , which closed in January .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [72, 85], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [44, 52], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "Contributors want to know that their funds will not only do good , they will do well , '' said J. Ezra Merkin , a money manager who heads Gabriel Capital and is the chairman of the investment committee of Yeshiva University and of UJA-Federation of New York .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000a3e5797', 'name': 'J. Ezra Merkin', 'pos': [95, 109], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000b5c756b', 'name': 'Gabriel Capital', 'pos': [138, 153], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Eliot Spitzer , the New York attorney general , submitted a report yesterday as part of his lawsuit against Maurice R. Greenberg , the former chief executive of American International Group , contending that Mr. Greenberg unfairly enriched himself and other A.I.G. executives in a series of transactions that violated the will of Cornelius Vander Starr , the company 's founder , and defrauded a foundation he created .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [0, 13], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [20, 28], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "Another team , on the business side , worked on a '' particularly important deal to us , '' said Google 's co-founder and co-president , Sergey Brin .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000742c6', 'name': 'Sergey Brin', 'pos': [137, 148], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000042acea', 'name': 'Google', 'pos': [97, 103], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "He said that Sergey Brin , one of Google 's founders and a mathematician by training , had proved that this breakdown was optimal .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000742c6', 'name': 'Sergey Brin', 'pos': [13, 24], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000042acea', 'name': 'Google', 'pos': [34, 40], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'His most recent communications chief , Steve Schmidt , also departed , to run the re-election campaign of Gov. Arnold Schwarzenegger of California .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000006567', 'name': 'Arnold Schwarzenegger', 'pos': [111, 132], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000000d0f6', 'name': 'California', 'pos': [136, 146], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "For Bob Schieffer , the interim anchor of the '' CBS Evening News '' since March 10 , no viewer 's opinion has been more important than that of Leslie Moonves , the chairman of CBS and co-president of its parent company , Viacom .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000037942f', 'name': 'Leslie Moonves', 'pos': [144, 158], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004b0af', 'name': 'CBS', 'pos': [49, 52], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "My view is that stocks really ca n't deliver the same returns in the future as in the past , unless we have a major decline in stock prices , '' said John Y. Campbell , a professor of economics at Harvard University and an adviser to the Social Security trustees on the issue in 2001 . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000006b864db', 'name': 'John Y. Campbell', 'pos': [150, 166], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000001c71d', 'name': 'Harvard University', 'pos': [197, 215], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "For all their differences in size and style , Peet 's and Starbucks are linked by their past : the current director of Peet 's , Gerald Baldwin , helped found Starbucks before selling to Howard Schultz , who built it into the ubiquitous brand of today .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000334d18', 'name': 'Howard Schultz', 'pos': [187, 201], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000142ff7', 'name': 'Starbucks', 'pos': [58, 67], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "For all their differences in size and style , Peet 's and Starbucks are linked by their past : the current director of Peet 's , Gerald Baldwin , helped found Starbucks before selling to Howard Schultz , who built it into the ubiquitous brand of today .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000334d18', 'name': 'Howard Schultz', 'pos': [187, 201], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000142ff7', 'name': 'Starbucks', 'pos': [58, 67], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'BellSouth , the third-largest regional Bell carrier , has not only been absent from talks that led to deals for AT&T and MCI but , according to its chief executive , F. Duane Ackerman , is very happy to go it alone , thank you .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000762c0b', 'name': 'F. Duane Ackerman', 'pos': [166, 183], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001e350b', 'name': 'BellSouth', 'pos': [0, 9], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "His campaign received a boost yesterday , when John J. Mack , a former president of Morgan Stanley and chief executive of Credit Suisse First Boston , was named the point man for the group 's effort .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000709902', 'name': 'John J. Mack', 'pos': [47, 59], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000003ad33f', 'name': 'Credit Suisse First Boston', 'pos': [122, 148], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "His campaign received a boost yesterday , when John J. Mack , a former president of Morgan Stanley and chief executive of Credit Suisse First Boston , was named the point man for the group 's effort .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000709902', 'name': 'John J. Mack', 'pos': [47, 59], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000086b00', 'name': 'Morgan Stanley', 'pos': [84, 98], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Of all the famous names associated with CBS News , the biggest and brightest on the marquee are Murrow , Cronkite and Rather , '' Mr. McManus said in the statement , invoking Edward R. Murrow and Walter Cronkite , two other men who could lay claim to being the face of CBS News over the years . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000132b8f', 'name': 'Walter Cronkite', 'pos': [196, 211], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001fa362', 'name': 'CBS News', 'pos': [40, 48], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Of all the famous names associated with CBS News , the biggest and brightest on the marquee are Murrow , Cronkite and Rather , '' Mr. McManus said in the statement , invoking Edward R. Murrow and Walter Cronkite , two other men who could lay claim to being the face of CBS News over the years . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000132b8f', 'name': 'Walter Cronkite', 'pos': [196, 211], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001fa362', 'name': 'CBS News', 'pos': [40, 48], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "What 's really important is the emergence of a political class that would agree on the rules of the game , '' said Fouad Ajami , who teaches international relations at Johns Hopkins University . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000045f7d3', 'name': 'Fouad Ajami', 'pos': [115, 126], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004c75a', 'name': 'Johns Hopkins University', 'pos': [168, 192], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'The chief executive and controlling shareholder of Four Seasons Hotels , Isadore Sharp , made a $ 3.7 billion buyout bid for the luxury hotel chain yesterday .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000005a99b3', 'name': 'Isadore Sharp', 'pos': [73, 86], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001e641b', 'name': 'Four Seasons Hotels', 'pos': [51, 70], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'Notes Al Leiter , who sparkled in postseason stints as a Fox Sports analyst , will join the YES Network in the coming days .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000003b0733', 'name': 'Al Leiter', 'pos': [6, 15], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000062ac01', 'name': 'YES Network', 'pos': [92, 103], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "But Stacey Snider , chairwoman of Universal Pictures , urged Mr. Silverman to sign Steve Carell , who was coming off a successful stint on '' The Daily Show . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000008de0d25', 'name': 'Stacey Snider', 'pos': [4, 17], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000024aaa6', 'name': 'Universal Pictures', 'pos': [34, 52], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "How did Democrats fail to exploit the false-but-helpful rumor of President George W. Bush 's involvement in Texas chainsaw massacres ? ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000951bd7', 'name': 'George W. Bush', 'pos': [75, 89], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003abf2', 'name': 'Texas', 'pos': [108, 113], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': 'But the problem is real , said Joseph Ansanelli , the chief executive and founder of Vontu , who has testified before Congress on privacy problems .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000004fbfd24', 'name': 'Joseph Ansanelli', 'pos': [31, 47], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000004f2acfd', 'name': 'Vontu', 'pos': [85, 90], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "In May 2002 , Under Secretary of State John R. Bolton sent a letter to Kofi Annan , secretary general of the United Nations , announcing that the United States did n't consider itself bound by the Rome Statute .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002250d', 'name': 'Kofi Annan', 'pos': [71, 81], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003e4c5', 'name': 'United Nations', 'pos': [109, 123], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'The software also determined , to the surprise of at least one Microsoft employee , that e-mail missives from Bill Gates were not necessarily urgent , since Gates tends to write long , discursive notes for employees to meditate on .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000009e99', 'name': 'Bill Gates', 'pos': [110, 120], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000026344', 'name': 'Microsoft', 'pos': [63, 72], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Michaels is expected to soon announce his move to NBC to call Sunday night games with John Madden , his partner on '' Monday Night '' at ABC , which has relinquished its rights to the games .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000dbcd41', 'name': 'John Madden', 'pos': [86, 97], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002ba8d', 'name': 'NBC', 'pos': [50, 53], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Time Warner has carried the Cablevision networks ' games without a contract since the start of 2004 ; since August , Eliot Spitzer , the New York attorney general , has brokered three extensions .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [117, 130], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [137, 145], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "The committee 's second report , issued March 29 , criticized the company for making '' false statements '' about its relationship with Kojo Annan , son of Kofi Annan , the United Nations secretary general .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002250d', 'name': 'Kofi Annan', 'pos': [156, 166], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003e4c5', 'name': 'United Nations', 'pos': [173, 187], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'BlackRock , a firm that has thrived under the vibrant , independent leadership of a core of top executives , headed by Laurence D. Fink , its chief executive , will now operate under a tighter leash .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006b5345', 'name': 'Laurence D. Fink', 'pos': [119, 135], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006b52b4', 'name': 'BlackRock', 'pos': [0, 9], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "This revised proposal is superior to the Verizon transaction , '' the chief executive of Qwest , Richard C. Notebaert , wrote in a letter to MCI 's board , outlining the proposal .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000562fe2c', 'name': 'Richard C. Notebaert', 'pos': [97, 117], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000018c40c', 'name': 'Qwest', 'pos': [89, 94], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Renewing ` Monday Night Football ' did not make financial sense for ABC , '' said George Bodenheimer , president of ABC Sports and ESPN , '' but it made great financial sense for ESPN . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000f049cb', 'name': 'George Bodenheimer', 'pos': [82, 100], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000008acdc', 'name': 'ESPN', 'pos': [131, 135], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Renewing ` Monday Night Football ' did not make financial sense for ABC , '' said George Bodenheimer , president of ABC Sports and ESPN , '' but it made great financial sense for ESPN . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000f049cb', 'name': 'George Bodenheimer', 'pos': [82, 100], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000008acdc', 'name': 'ESPN', 'pos': [131, 135], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'Mr. Falco and his new deputy , Ron Grant , made their first moves yesterday to run AOL for the long haul by doing something its employees have become accustomed to in the six tumultuous years since the company merged with Time Warner : reorganizing the executive suite .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000006aa3e6f', 'name': 'Ron Grant', 'pos': [31, 40], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000000565b', 'name': 'AOL', 'pos': [83, 86], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "The fact that Microsoft 's chief executive , Steven A. Ballmer , and its chairman and former chief executive , Bill Gates , have chosen not to blog leaves an embarrassing silence at the top that the combined clacking of those underlings can not fill .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000009e99', 'name': 'Bill Gates', 'pos': [111, 121], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000026344', 'name': 'Microsoft', 'pos': [14, 23], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "After the drug bill 's passage , Jacob Hacker and Theodore Marmor of Yale University estimated that a sensible bill could have delivered twice as much coverage for the same price .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000045c2079', 'name': 'Jacob Hacker', 'pos': [33, 45], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000042025', 'name': 'Yale University', 'pos': [69, 84], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Still , the defection of Ms. Couric from '' Today , '' the top-rated morning program for more than a decade , is being taken so seriously at NBC that her former boss on the program , Jeff Zucker , now chief executive of NBC Universal Television , has been gathering executives for regular meetings intended to guard against complacency , in both the evening and morning time slots .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000003fe302', 'name': 'Jeff Zucker', 'pos': [183, 194], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000045f512', 'name': 'NBC Universal Television', 'pos': [220, 244], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'The relationship between Johnson & Johnson and Guidant continued to slide as Eliot Spitzer , the New York attorney general , formally announced a lawsuit he had filed accusing Guidant of fraud in connection with sales of a defibrillator model that short-circuited in some cases .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [77, 90], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [97, 105], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': 'The accord , in which Universal agreed to pay $ 12 million to New York charities , was the biggest so far in a sweeping investigation of the music industry that has been led by Eliot Spitzer , the New York attorney general .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [177, 190], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [62, 70], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': 'The accord , in which Universal agreed to pay $ 12 million to New York charities , was the biggest so far in a sweeping investigation of the music industry that has been led by Eliot Spitzer , the New York attorney general .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [177, 190], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [62, 70], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "And in a nod to '' new media , '' which is not exactly new anymore , Arianna Huffington joined the panel , which also included Mark P. Mays of Clear Channel Communications , Cathleen Black of Hearst Magazines and Stephen B. Burke of Comcast .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000007baa7db', 'name': 'Stephen B. Burke', 'pos': [213, 229], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001c1c7e', 'name': 'Comcast', 'pos': [233, 240], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'The commission -- headed by Richard Parsons , the chairman of Time Warner , and Geoffrey Canada , a highly regarded pioneer of antipoverty programs -- seems to have searched everywhere for ideas that work .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000808830', 'name': 'Richard Parsons', 'pos': [28, 43], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000009231c', 'name': 'Time Warner', 'pos': [62, 73], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Any spammer worth his salt is not going to follow Can Spam , '' said Scott Petry , Postini 's founder and senior vice president for products and engineering , '' because it would be filtered out immediately . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000006ed5e03', 'name': 'Scott Petry', 'pos': [69, 80], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000006b110c2', 'name': 'Postini', 'pos': [83, 90], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'In it Mr. Chirac and Kofi Annan , the secretary general of the United Nations , both tall and snappy in blue serge suits , were greeting Chief Laukalbi from Vanuatu and his nephew , Jerry Napat , shirtless in straw skirts .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002250d', 'name': 'Kofi Annan', 'pos': [21, 31], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000003e4c5', 'name': 'United Nations', 'pos': [63, 77], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "The presence of dozens of billionaires , however eye-catching , is of less moment than the absence of millions of small and medium businesses , '' Stephen Kotkin , director of Princeton University 's Russian studies program , said in an e-mail interview .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000a472cf', 'name': 'Stephen Kotkin', 'pos': [147, 161], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000002fa40', 'name': 'Princeton University', 'pos': [176, 196], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'In France , Interior Minister Nicolas Sarkozy called in the chiefs of his law enforcement and intelligence services for an emergency meeting .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000002ae131', 'name': 'Nicolas Sarkozy', 'pos': [30, 45], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000d4492b', 'name': 'France', 'pos': [3, 9], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': 'John J. Mack , chief executive of Morgan Stanley , received a $ 41.1 million bonus last week -- also a record , but a record that lasted less than a week .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000709902', 'name': 'John J. Mack', 'pos': [0, 12], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000086b00', 'name': 'Morgan Stanley', 'pos': [34, 48], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "B1 Governor 's Race Heats Up Nassau County Executive Thomas R. Suozzi wasted no time in taunting Attorney General Eliot Spitzer , his opponent in their likely fight for New York governor , calling him '' overly reliant '' on donations from lawyers .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000025cf02', 'name': 'Eliot Spitzer', 'pos': [114, 127], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000054dd5d', 'name': 'New York', 'pos': [169, 177], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "The Congressional Budget Office recently published studies of the plan from the President 's Commission to Strengthen Social Security and the plan favored by Democrats , developed by a Massachusetts Institute of Technology professor , Peter Diamond , and a Clinton adviser , Peter R. Orszag www.cbo.gov/SocialSecurity.cfm#pt3 .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000b1b2e7', 'name': 'Peter R. Orszag', 'pos': [275, 290], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000040f7c4', 'name': 'Congressional Budget Office', 'pos': [4, 31], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Bill Gates , Microsoft 's chairman , said the companies decided to put their rivalry behind them more than two years ago , when Jeff Hawkins , a Palm founder , visited Microsoft to discuss a development and marketing agreement .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000009e99', 'name': 'Bill Gates', 'pos': [0, 10], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000026344', 'name': 'Microsoft', 'pos': [13, 22], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Bill Gates , Microsoft 's chairman , said the companies decided to put their rivalry behind them more than two years ago , when Jeff Hawkins , a Palm founder , visited Microsoft to discuss a development and marketing agreement .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000009e99', 'name': 'Bill Gates', 'pos': [0, 10], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000026344', 'name': 'Microsoft', 'pos': [13, 22], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Mexico 's economy has performed poorly since President Vicente Fox took office six years ago .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000405a4', 'name': 'Vicente Fox', 'pos': [55, 66], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000a483f7', 'name': 'Mexico', 'pos': [0, 6], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': "Alfred Blumstein , a criminologist at Carnegie Mellon University in Pittsburgh , said an increase in crime in the last couple of years in some places could be a result of police efforts ' being diverted to fighting terrorism , budget cuts that have reduced social services and prisons , and fewer job opportunities for young people in poorer communities . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000571b31d', 'name': 'Alfred Blumstein', 'pos': [0, 16], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000005ef9f', 'name': 'Carnegie Mellon University', 'pos': [38, 64], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "PAGE A8 Rules With a Familiar Ring William H. Swanson , chief executive of the military contractor Raytheon , has reaped publicity and praise with his list of 33 '' Unwritten Rules of Management . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000197761', 'name': 'William H. Swanson', 'pos': [35, 53], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000018f51d', 'name': 'Raytheon', 'pos': [99, 107], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "In doing so , ReganBooks , which is part of HarperCollins , which is in turn owned by Rupert Murdoch 's News Corporation , would be one of the few major book imprints to be based outside Manhattan and one of the first to leave New York for the West Coast .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000033ef1', 'name': 'Rupert Murdoch', 'pos': [86, 100], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000000c718e', 'name': 'News Corporation', 'pos': [104, 120], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "In comments to television critics in June , Leslie Moonves , the chief executive of CBS , criticized Showtime as '' a little too much of an off-Broadway play , '' more interested in pleasing critics than in drawing big audiences .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000037942f', 'name': 'Leslie Moonves', 'pos': [44, 58], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004b0af', 'name': 'CBS', 'pos': [84, 87], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'While Mr. Knight has had conversations with Laurence D. Fink , the chief executive of BlackRock , and Robert E. Diamond Jr. , the president of Barclays , people briefed on the search say that he and the board are now focusing on Mr. Mack as the best chance to unify Morgan Stanley , given his experience at the firm .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006b5345', 'name': 'Laurence D. Fink', 'pos': [44, 60], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000006b52b4', 'name': 'BlackRock', 'pos': [86, 95], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'Prozac Nation Now that Bob and Harvey Weinstein have left Miramax Films , this mini-major seems to be conducting a video fire sale , dumping many of the titles on DVD that the company produced or acquired over the years but never quite believed in enough to release in theaters .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000057c3f1', 'name': 'Harvey Weinstein', 'pos': [31, 47], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000008792d', 'name': 'Miramax Films', 'pos': [58, 71], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'The French fall collections , which had their lumpy bits , ended Sunday night with a barrage of talent : Marc Jacobs at Louis Vuitton , Alber Elbaz at Lanvin and Stefano Pilati at Yves Saint Laurent .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000061118f', 'name': 'Marc Jacobs', 'pos': [105, 116], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000037a41c', 'name': 'Louis Vuitton', 'pos': [120, 133], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': 'PCCW is led by Richard Li , its founder and chairman , who is also the 38-year-old son of the Hong Kong multibillionaire Li Ka-shing .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f80000000001e1955', 'name': 'Richard Li', 'pos': [15, 25], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000014b64d', 'name': 'PCCW', 'pos': [0, 4], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "It is important that Bob keeps his deal , '' said Sumner Redstone , the 83-year-old chairman of Paramount 's corporate parent , Viacom , and a close friend of the producer . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000147ed6', 'name': 'Sumner Redstone', 'pos': [50, 65], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000147ec8', 'name': 'Viacom', 'pos': [128, 134], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Bucknell officials say they hope that is a message a national audience learns through two broadcasts this weekend on CBS , a network run by a Bucknell alumnus , Leslie Moonves . ''", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000037942f', 'name': 'Leslie Moonves', 'pos': [161, 175], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004b0af', 'name': 'CBS', 'pos': [117, 120], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': 'People Citigroup has named William R. Rhodes , its senior vice chairman , to be president and chief executive of Citibank and president of Citicorp Holdings .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000671918', 'name': 'William R. Rhodes', 'pos': [27, 44], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000017cbd3', 'name': 'Citibank', 'pos': [113, 121], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "Amazon.com 's chief executive , Jeffrey P. Bezos , said that '' Amazon Prime members are shopping more and doing more cross-shopping , '' but he did not provide the information necessary to judge whether those sales were profitable for the company .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000010f8c9', 'name': 'Jeffrey P. Bezos', 'pos': [32, 48], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000009ba2e', 'name': 'Amazon.com', 'pos': [0, 10], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
{'text': "And many choreographers have extracted its elegant pas de deux as a showpiece on its own , as George Balanchine did in 1950 with his '' Sylvia Pas de Deux '' for Maria Tallchief and Nicholas Magallanes of the New York City Ballet .", 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000165019', 'name': 'George Balanchine', 'pos': [94, 111], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000246bd5', 'name': 'New York City Ballet', 'pos': [209, 229], 'type': 'LOCATION'}}
{'text': 'And John Carmack , developer of the Doom and Quake computer games , has founded Armadillo Aerospace near Dallas and has already put in $ 1 million to build a suborbital craft .', 'relation': '/business/person/company', 'h': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f800000000004c5df', 'name': 'John Carmack', 'pos': [4, 16], 'type': 'PERSON'}, 't': {'id': '/guid/9202a8c04000641f8000000000140d1a', 'name': 'Armadillo Aerospace', 'pos': [80, 99], 'type': 'ORGANIZATION'}}
